<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Barbara Class</title>
    <link>https://barbaraclass.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://barbaraclass.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://barbaraclass.com/media/BClass.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://barbaraclass.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Social behaviour and disease ecology in Eastern water dragons (Post-doc 2, 2020-2021)</title>
      <link>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My second post-doc on urban Eastern Water dragons (EWD, &lt;em&gt;Intellagama Lesueurii&lt;/em&gt;) allowed me to extend my research to new questions at the intersection between social behaviour, disease ecology, and urban evolutionary ecology. I kept developing my skills in variance partitioning approaches (e.g. using DHGLMMs), I also started to use social network analyses combined with simulations. In particular, I have been involved in a variety of collaborative projects such as i) Assessing the virulence, dynamics and survival costs of a recent emerging infectious fungal disease in EWD (with Shweta Bansal’s lab, Georgetown University, USA);  ii) Modelling long-term social avoidances and their consequences for social network structure (with Amiyaal Ilani, Bar-Ilan University, IL); iii) Investigating the repeatability, plasticity and predictability of social behaviour, temperature, and their relationships in EWD (with Shinichi Nakagawa, UNSW, AU).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Evolutionary quantitative genetics in the wild (Post-doc 1, 2017-2019)</title>
      <link>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first post-doc, I continued to apply quantitative genetics methods to study evolutionary questions in wild birds. This project allowed me to deepen my knowledge in quantitative genetics and include a wider variety of traits, while exploring more questions related to sexual selection: i) I studied lifetime changes (genotype-age interactions) in great tits’ (&lt;em&gt;Parus major&lt;/em&gt;) exploration behaviour, in collaboration with Kees van Oers (NIOO, the Netherlands); ii) I studied the multi-level relationships between early life body mass and behaviour at fledging in blue tits; iii) I tested whether shared environmental effects can bias phenotypic estimates of assortative mating in wild blue tits;  iv) I studied the potential indirect genetic benefits of mate choice in blue tits by estimating genetic correlations between blue plumage coloration and measures of performance in nestlings; v) I estimated dominance genetic variance for various traits in blue tit nestlings and explored the consequences of ignoring it for estimating evolutionary potential in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Evolutionary quantitative genetics of animal personality in the wild (PhD thesis, 2013-2017)</title>
      <link>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barbaraclass.com/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Ph.D. thesis aimed to provide a quantitative genetics overview of personality in a wild population of blue tits (&lt;em&gt;Cyanistes caeruleus&lt;/em&gt;). In the first part of my thesis, I showed that two behaviours measured during handling are heritable and under selection. The second part addressed the development of animal personality and heritable lifetime changes in behaviour. In the last part of my thesis, I developed a statistical approach to estimate assortative mating based on personality in wild populations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
